Noah T. Erickson

(971) 285-5227 • noahterickson@gmail.com noahericksonpdx.com

Embedded systems engineer with 4+ years of experience in firmware development for the outdoor power equipment industry. Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities, and possesses a wide range of technical skills. Enjoys being part of a team and thrives in high pressure and challenging environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Blount International

Portland, Oregon

Embedded Systems Engineer

June 2015 - Present

- Designed and implemented motor control firmware for multiple product lines in the outdoor power equipment industry.
- Developed testing and debug interfaces for tool diagnostics and data-logging.
- Designed test fixtures and firmware for functional circuit testing and end of line testing.

Daimler Trucks North America

Portland, Oregon

Mechatronics Intern

March 2014 - September 2014

• Failure analysis of 12V systems on trucks.

Papa Murphy's

Portland, Oregon

Lead Prep

March 2010 - June 2015

• Managed up to eight people, opened and closed the store, ordered product and managed inventory.

PROJECTS

ICS 536-E Concrete Cutting Chainsaw

Blount International

- AC mains or generator powered 3600W concrete chainsaw grinder.
- Designed and implemented motor control firmware and control interface for power supply.
- Designed and implemented communication protocol for diagnostics and data-logging.

Oregon 120V Professional Series

Blount International

- Battery powered suite of outdoor power equipment targeting commercial landscaping market.
- Developed motor control firmware and communication protocols to interface with battery.

Viking Motorsport's Digital Dashboard

Portland State University

 $ECE\ 412/413$ - $Senior\ Design$

Fall 2014 - Spring 2015

- A team of myself and four others designed a digital dashboard and integrated it on Portland State University's Viking Motorsport's electric vehicle.
- Skills learned: Embedded system design, communication protocols, time management, budget management, inter-team communication, rapid prototyping, various tools.

EDUCATION

Portland State University

Portland, Oregon

BS Electrical and Computer Engineering

Graduated June 2016

PATENTS

- United States Patent No. 20,180,323,740
- United States Patent No. 20,180,358,918